Onondaga County Community College Presidents' Collection
Onondaga Community College
- Office of Dr. Francis Almstead (February 1962 - December 1967), 1962 - 1967; Archival material related to the Presidency of Dr. Francis Almstead. Almstead was the first President of Onondaga Community College. He was President from February 1962 to December 1965. Almstead obtained a B.S. and M.S. 
  - Correspondence with Onondaga Community College Faculty and Staff, 1962 - 1967; Letters and memos to and from OCC faculty. (Box-folder PRE1 - 4)
    - Letter from John Henderson to John Leonard Regarding Visit to Mutual of New York, March 24, 1965; Typed copy of letter by John Henderson, Chairman of Technological Department to John Leonard, Vice-President of Personnel of Mutual of New York regarding a visit to Mutual of New York. Visit was to gain insight into what training is needed for Mutual of New York Staff.
    - Memo to Alvin G. Mardon Regarding Comparison of 1962 and 1965 Academic Year, April 6, 1965; Typed memo to Alvin G. Mardon, fulfilling Mardon's request for a comparison of the number of faculty, investment, and budget projections of the 1962 and 1965 year.
    - Memo to Office Staff Regarding Columbus Day, October 6, 1965; Typed memo to Office Staff suggesting that the College observe Columbus Day on the Friday after Thanksgiving as Columbus Day falls during the middle of the term.
    - Memo from William F. Krall Regarding Dennis Sands, October 28, 1965; Typed memo from William F. Krall giving a review of instructor Dennis Sands. Recommends promoting him to Assistant Professor.
    - Memo to Faculty Regarding Meeting on Personnel Policies, November 12, 1965; Typed memo to faculty stating that a scheduled meeting would be for teaching faculty only and the topic would be personnel policies.
  - Memorandum from State Education Department on Civil Defense, 1962 (Box-folder PRE1 - 5)
    - Keynote Address given by General F.W. Farrell, Director, New York State Civil Defense Commission, "Civil Defense and Fallout Shelters", February 15, 1962
    - Check list - Civil Defense - from James Allen, Jr. President of the University and Commissioner of Education, Albany, N.Y., October 26, 1962
  - Correspondence with State Education Department, 1962 - 1965 (Box-folder PRE2 - 2)
  - Report of Visit to OCC Syracuse, NY April 21-23, 1965 by Henry Parcinski, Alliance College and Ray A. Miller, York Junior College, May 5, 1965 (Box-folder PRE2 - 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1965 (Box-folder PRE2 - 2)
  - Crusade for Opportunity, 1965 (Box-folder PRE2 - 4)
    - Contract with Syracuse Schools, 1965
    - Introduction to Crusade for Opportunity Education Program with Attachment 1-6, 1965
    - Syracuse Action for Youth, Mayors Commission for Youth, Inc., 1965
    - Summary of the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964, December 1, 1964
    - Application for Community Action Program, 1965
    - Crusade for Opportunity Education Committee Roster, 1965
    - Crusade for Opportunity Education Division Memorandum, 1965
    - Crusade for Opportunity Education Division Coorespondence, 1964 - 1965
    - Crusade for Opportunity Education Division Minutes, 1964 - 1966
  - Academic Affairs, 1963 - 1965 (Box PRE2A)
  - Technologies, 1965 (Box PRE2A)
  - Civil Defense, 1962 (Box PRE2A)
  - Citizens Foundation, 1965 (Box PRE2A)
  - Census Survey, 1965 (Box PRE2A)
  - Cabinet, 1964 - 1965 (Box PRE2A)
  - Dean Howard Burtis, 1964 - 1965 (Box PRE2A)
  - Speeches, Reports, 1963 - 1965 (Box PRE2A)
  - Secondary Schools, 1964, 1967 (Box PRE2A)
  - President's Luncheon, 1962 - 1965 (Box PRE2A)
  - Onondaga County, 1963 - 1965 (Box PRE2A)
  - Internship for Fellows in Academic Administration, 1965 (Box PRE2A)
  - General Correspondence/Memos, 1962 - 1965 (Box PRE2A)
  - Dr. Almstead's obituary, 1965 (Box-folder PRE2-5)
- Office of Dr. Karl D. Larsen, Acting President (January 1966 to June 1966), 1965 - 1966; Archival material related to the Acting Presidency of Dr. Karl D. Larsen. Dr. Larsen received his B.A. and M.A. from the University of Maine, and his Ph. D. from the Penn State University. Prior to coming to Onondaga Community College Dr. Larsen was an instructor at the University of Maine, Layfayette College, Stevens Institute, and served in the U.S. military. In 1963 Dr. Larsen became the Dean of Faculty and Professor of Physics at Onondaga Community College. He became acting President of OCC in 1966, serving in this capacity from January through June. Dr. Larsen went on to teach at the University of Bridgeport. Dr. Larsen was an author of many research papers, and served as a consultant in the field of Forensic Physics. Dr. Larsen died in 1990 in Bridgeport, Connecticut.
  - Coorespondence, 1965 - 1966 (Box-folder PRE3 - 1)
  - Memorandum to Board of Trustees and Committees, 1963 - 1965 (Box-folder PRE3 - 2,3)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1990; Contains Dr. Larsen's obituary (Box-folder PRE3 - 4)
- Office of Dr. Marvin A. Rapp (June 1966 - Aug. 1973), 1966 - 1973; Archival material related to the Presidency of Dr. Marvin A. Rapp. B.A. from Colgate University, Magna Cum Laude and Phi Beta Kappa; Master’s and Ph.D. from Duke University; U. S. Army Air Corps Intelligence (World War II); Vice President and Executive Dean of Nassau Community College, Mitchell Field, Long Island, NY 1961 to 1966. After OCC, Dr. Rapp was appointed Special Assistant to the Council on County Colleges in Trenton, NJ; continued his publications on the history of New York State with a particular interest in the Erie Canal and in Ontario County; served on the Board of Trustees for Finger Lakes Community College; and received the New York State Outstanding Community College.
  - Inauguration, November 2, 1968 (Box-folder PRE4 - 1)
  - Memorandum, 1966 - 1973 (Box-folder PRE4 - 2)
  - Correspondence, 1962 - 1978 (Box PRE12, Box PRE13, Box PRE34)
  - Directives to the Faculty, 1967 - 1972 (Box-folder PRE4 - 4)
  - Recommendations for Students, 1968 - 1971 (Box-folder PRE4 - 5)
  - Administrative Council, 1964 - 1965 (Box-folder PRE5 - 1)
  - Adminstrative Conference, 1966 - 1971 (Box-folder PRE5 - 2,3,4,5,6,7, Box-folder PRE6 - 1,2,3,4,5,6,7)
  - Subject Files, 1966 - 1973 (Box 7 -)
    - Advisory Council - Downtown and Uptown, 1971 - 1982 (Box 7)
    - Association of Independent Colleges and Universities (AAUA) Correspondence, 1971 (Box-folder 8 - 2)
    - Association of Independent Colleges and Universities (AAUA) Grievance Report, 1973 (Box-folder 8 - 3)
    - Campus Academic Plan and Campus Development Plan, 1968 (Box-folder 8 - 4)
    - Campus Floor Plans, 1968 (Box-folder 8 - 5)
    - Dmohowski Case, 1964 (Box-folder 8 - 6,7,8,9, Box 18-19)
    - Circumstantial Material, 1965 - 1973 (Box-folder 8 - 10)
    - Personnel Policy, 1967 (Box-folder 8 - 11)
    - Dr. George W. Angell Survey (unionizing faculty), 1971 - 1972 (Box-folder 9 - 1)
    - Annual Reports, 1964 - 1971 (Box-folder 9 - 2)
    - Articulation, 1962 - 1973 (Box-folder 9 - 3)
    - Black Student Concerns, 1969 - 1971 (Box-folder 9 - 4)
    - Budget Battle, 1969 (Box-folder 9 - 5)
    - Campaign (Onondaga Hill campus), 1970 - 1971 (Box-folder 9 - 6)
    - Community College Law, 1968 - 1972 (Box-folder 9 - 7)
    - Campus Unrest, 1969 - 1973 (Box 10)
    - Community Health Information and Planning (CHIPS) Study, April, 1967 (Box-folder 11 - 1)
    - External Degree Program, 1972 (Box-folder 11 - 2)
    - Nursing Education - Community Planning Group, 1969 - 1972 (Box 11)
    - Decade of Achievement, 1972 (Box-folder 14 - 1)
    - Development of OCC, 1961 (Box-folder 14 - 2)
    - Fire Inspection Report, 1972 (Box-folder 14 - 3)
    - Education Amendments of 1972 (Box-folder 14 - 4)
    - Organizational Charts and Administrative Responsibilites, 1969 - 1972 (Box-folder 14 - 5)
    - Paramedical Program, 1970 - 1971 (Box-folder 14 - 6)
    - Racial Integration, 1972 (Box-folder 14 - 7)
    - Research Panel, 1971 (Box-folder 14 - 6)
    - State Commission Evaluation Form, 1965 - 1970 (Box-folder 14 - 9)
    - Academic Speeches, 1962 - 1970 (Box-folder 14 - 10)
    - Transfer Summary Reports, 1969 - 1970 (Box-folder 14 - 11)
    - ECCO - Educational and Cultural Center Serving Onondaga and Oswego Counties, 1967 - 1972 (Box-folder 15 - 1, Box-folder 16 - 4)
    - Economic Education, 1966 - 1972 (Box-folder 15 - 2,3, Box-folder 16 - 3)
    - Economic Education Council, 1970 - 1971 (Box-folder 16 - 1)
    - Regents External Degree, 1976 - 1979 (Box-folder 16 - 2)
    - Inauguration, 1968 (Box 17, Box 20)
    - Legislation Affecting the County, 1966 - 1968 (Box 21)
    - Master Development Plan, 1967, 1968, 1968, 1971, 1992, 1994, 1995 (Box 22-23)
    - Metropolitan Development, 1967 - 1969 (Box-folder 24 - 1)
    - Dr. Rapp's Reports to SUNY, 1968 - 1972 (Box-folder 24 - 2)
    - Community Foundation of Syracuse and Onondaga County, N. James Polney Fund, 1968 (Box-folder PRE25-2)
    - Occupational Education Program (OEP), 1971 (Box-folder PRE25-3)
    - Peace Corps., 1966 - 1970 (Box-folder PRE25-4)
    - Postal Reform, 1969 - 1970 (Box-folder PRE25-5)
    - Purposes and Philosophies of OCC, 1964 - 1968 (Box-folder PRE25-6)
    - Regents External Degree Program, 1972 - 1978 (Box-folder PRE25-7)
    - Regionalism I, II, III, 1971 - 1973 (PRE26)
    - Reports, 1965 - 1973 (Box PRE27)
      - Hobson Report, 1965
      - Ingler Report, 1969, 1973
      - Sawyer Report, 1967 - 1968
    - Simonian - Soil Management, 1969 (Box PRE27)
    - Sutton Real Estate - Midtown Plaza, 1966 - 1973 (Box PRE27)
    - Sutton, Malcolm - Lease - Midtown Plaza, 1967 - 1971 (Box PRE27)
    - Syracuse City School DIstrict, 1964 - 1973 (Box PRE27)
    - Transition Plan, 1973 (Box PRE27)
    - Urban Center, 1966 - 1968 (Box PRE27)
    - Very Special Arts Festival, 1980 (Box PRE31)
    - Vocational Education Act of 1963, 1964 - 1971 (Box PRE31)
    - Vocational Surveys, 1964 - 1967 (Box PRE31)
    - Women's Programs, 1964 - 1967 (Box PRE31)
    - State Education Department Material, 1968 - 1970 (Box PRE33)
    - Accreditation, November 3, 1969 (Box-folder PRE32-1)
    - Allied Health Professions, 1968 - 1972 (Box-folder PRE32-2)
    - Dr. Rapp's Appointment Letter, May 26, 1966 (Box-folder PRE32-3)
    - Civil Rights, 1973 (Box-folder PRE32-4)
    - Overpayment of OCC Administrators, 1971 - 1973 (Box-folder PRE32-5)
    - Compliant Letters, 1968 - 1973 (Box-folder PRE32-6)
    - Curriculum Reports, July 6, 1973 (Box-folder PRE32-7)
    - Economic Chair - OCC, 1973 (Box-folder PRE32-8)
    - Human Rights - Melfi, Joseph, 1975 (Box-folder PRE32-9)
    - Mulligan, George - non-reappointment case, 1966 (Box-folder PRE32-10)
    - New Campus, 1967 (Box-folder PRE32-11)
    - Onondaga Plan, 1968 - 1969 (Box-folder PRE32-12)
    - Vocational Education, 1965 - 1970 (Box-folder PRE32-13)
  - Construction Site Literature, 1952 - 1984
    - Recommendation for an Urban Location, January 6, 1964 (Box-folder PRE28-1)
    - Community College Temporary Quarters, 1962 (Box-folder PRE28-2)
    - Recommendations for Town of Onondaga Site, 1963 - 1965 (Box-folder PRE28-3)
    - Committee for Campus Planning, 1962 - 1970 (Box-folder PRE28-4)
    - SUNY Physical Space Inventory, March, 1968 (Box-folder PRE28-5)
    - Site Space Requirements, 1967 - 1973 (Box-folder PRE28-6)
    - Campus Construction, 1967 - 1973 (Box-folder PRE28-7)
    - Campus Construction Blueprints, 1965 (Box-folder PRE28-8)
    - Campus Construction Correspondence, 1962 - 1972 (Box-folder PRE28-9-12)
    - Campus Construction Interim Report, May 23, 1972 (Box-folder PRE28-13)
    - Barbino Property on Onondaga Hill, 1978 (Box-folder PRE29-1)
    - Completion of Capital Construction Program, 1973 (Box-folder PRE29-2)
    - Clark, Clark, Mills and Gilson Reports and Change Orders, 1970 - 1972 (Box-folder PRE29-3)
    - Campus Construction Final Phase, 1971 (Box-folder PRE29-4)
    - Campus Construction Site Committee, 1962 - 1973 (Box-folder PRE29-6)
    - Correspondence with Clark, Clark, Millis and Gilson, 1967 - 1972 (Box-folder PRE29-6)
    - Campus Construction Site - SUNY, 1963 - 1972 (Box-folder PRE29-6)
    - Clark, Clark, Millis & Gilson - Roofs, 1986 (Box-folder PRE28A-1)
    - History of Clark, Clark, Millis & Gilson, 1984 (Box-folder PRE28A-2)
    - Site Building and Grounds Memos, 1966 - 1973 (Box-folder PRE28A-3)
    - Subsurface Investigation Onondaga Community College Campus Site by Earl Apfel, April, 1967 (Box-folder PRE28A-4)
    - Site Construction Coorespondence, 1969 - 1974 (Box-folder PRE28A-5)
    - Location Possibilities for Onondaga Community College, December 26, 1961 (Box-folder PRE28A-6)
    - Blueprints and Plans for Proposed Sites, 1952 - 1972 (Box-folder PRE28A-7)
  - Academic Programs, Policies and Procedures, 1973 - 1984 (Box PRE30)
  - Organizational Charts and Re-organizational Charts, 1964 - 1996 (Box PRE32)
  - Speeches, 1951 - 1973 (Box-folder PRE4-6, Box PRE35)
  - Personal Papers, 1958, 1961, 1967-1973 and undated (Box PRE36, Box PRE37)
  - Assistant to President Rapp, 1971 - 1973; Murphy, Emmett McCaul, Michael Edwards, Ellie (Box 38)
  - Charles, Harvey - Acting President, August, 1969 - December, 1969
    - Educational and Cultural Center Serving Onondaga and Oswego Counties(ECCO), 1969 - 1970 (Box 39)
  - Obituary and Biography of Dr. Rapp, July, 1999 (Box 37)
- Office of Interim President Dr. Roy Price, August, 1973 - May, 1975; Archival material related to the Interim Presidency of Dr. Roy Price. Dr. Price served as President of Onondaga Community College from 1973 to 1975. Dr. Price received a B.A. in Philosophy from University of Chicago; Ed.M. and Ed.D. from Harvard; retired as Chair of Doctoral Programs in Social Science at Syracuse University. After serving as Interim President, he continued at OCC as a consultant. Price died May 25, 1992, in DeWitt, NY.